[
    {
        "question": "1. How would you define UX design?",
        "answer": "Your interviewer already knows what UX design is. What they expect from you is to explain UX design in your words. Interviewers prefer not to receive a generic textbook definition of a concept or topic. It always helps to do some research.\nOne of the most effective ways to answer this question is through real-life examples. You can talk about how co-founder Joe Gebbia attributes Airbnb to becoming a $10 billion company to UX design. You can also talk about Jeff Bezos’ decision to allocate 100 times more budget to customer experience than advertising in the initial days of Amazon.\nWhatever you say, the key point to remember is that UX design makes websites, apps, and other products easy to use and customer friendly.\nTake our UI UX Design course and master the skills you need to become a successful UI/UX designer!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. How is UX design different from UI design?",
        "answer": "The terms UI and UX are used interchangeably most of the time. What interviewers are interested in is whether you have a clear understanding of what UX design entails and what it does not encompass.\nA lot of companies have a combined UI/UX design team. You have to communicate the difference between the two distinct roles. While the UI team ensures that the product looks good, the UX team makes sure that the product works effectively and efficiently.\nYou can also use this opportunity to talk about your previous work experience with UI teams, collaborations, and different roles.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is meant by design thinking?",
        "answer": "This is where the interviewer is trying to understand your approach to design. You should explain your approach to design and take them through your design process. Tell them about your strategy for good design and how you develop your design concepts.\nTalk about the different stages involved in the process of design thinking.\nEmpathize – The first step is to empathically understand the problem that needs solving. Here, you would consult experts and observe people’s experiences to fully empathize with them.\nDefine – In the second step, you combine the information you collected in the first step. Then you analyze it to define the main problem.\nIdeate – In this step, you start coming up with ideas while keeping the user’s needs in mind.\nPrototype – In the fourth step, the design team comes up with scaled-down versions of the product or the features to see if the solutions work.\nTest – In the final step, you test the product and its features, utilizing the best solutions identified in the previous stage.\nFeeling prepared for your next UI/UX interview?\nChallenge yourself with our quiz\nTake a Quiz",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What makes a good UX designer?",
        "answer": "Remember not to stick to any textbook definitions. Instead, infuse your own unique perspective and personal style into your response. With this answer, you should emphasize the skills that make up a good UX designer.\nA good UX designer should be able to use empathy to understand what the user needs and try to come up with the best solution.\nThey should be capable of handling feedback. They should constantly ask for it.\nThey would work really hard to improve the product and themselves in the process.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the important skills for a UX designer?",
        "answer": "The most important skills for a UX designer are as follows:\nPrototyping, user flows, wireframing, and mockups\nUX designers should envision what the product will look like. According to the stage of the product development process, they’ll need to create wireframes, high- or low-fidelity prototypes, user flows, or mockups.\nVisual design and design software\nUX designers need to use visual design software to create the visual design elements of a product. They need to be proficient in using tools such as typography, color theory, icons, etc.\nCollaboration\nUX designers have to collaborate with other teams regularly. They need to know how to work as part of a team.\nCommunication and presentation\nWhile collaborating, UX designers have to communicate. Good communication skills are important for them to get better insights from customers. Good presentation skills are important to communicate ideas with stakeholders.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Why did you choose UX design?",
        "answer": "It goes without saying that you chose UX design because it excites you, and you’re passionate about it. Refrain from saying things like, “It seemed easy,” or, “It pays well”. That’s not what the interviewer wants to hear. You can answer this question by focusing on the qualities that make you a good UX designer. You could talk about the following soft skills, for example:\nProblem-solving – You’re good at solving problems and you love finding creative ways to solve challenges.\nEmpathetic – You’re empathetic by nature and love understanding customer behavior.\nCurious – You enjoy learning new things and being updated with new technological trends.\nApart from this, you can also talk about how well you manage your time. You can also talk about some hard skills that are required by UX designers.\nVisual elements – You can explain how you’ve always had an affinity toward visual design.\nStoryboarding – You can also tell them about your passion for storyboarding.\nWireframing – You could also talk about how wireframing comes naturally to you and that you enjoy it.\nMastering UI/UX design tools are really important to be a successful UX/UI designer. Have a look at our blog on top UI/UX design tools to master!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Show the interviewer your portfolio",
        "answer": "This is one of the most asked questions in a UX designer interview. The interviewer doesn’t just want to see your portfolio, they want you to walk them through it. This helps them understand your creative process. You should tell the interviewer why you designed things the way you did. Explain the target market, the problem, and why did you choose the solution that you did.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Explain your design process.",
        "answer": "The interviewer is interested in knowing about your thought process. They want to know your approach to the problem and also why you use that particular approach. An important aspect to mention here would be research – how you conducted user interviews by yourself or via a team of UX researchers.\nTake them through the design process – tell them what you chose to do and why. Don’t forget to talk about usability testing – how you got your design validated.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What’s your favorite project that you’ve worked on?",
        "answer": "You would have included your favorite project in your UI UX portfolio. When you’re taking the interviewer through your portfolio, make sure you talk about your favorites and why you liked them.\nRemember to explain why this project was different from others. Was it a personal project or maybe a passion project? Was it your favorite because it challenged you and made you approach the problem in an innovative way?\nThe interviewer is just trying to understand what excites you so they can further understand your way of thinking.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Tell me about a time when a project didn’t go as planned. How did you fix it?",
        "answer": "This question is your chance of talking about your problem-solving skills. The interviewer will also be interested in knowing that you can stay calm under pressure. You must have faced a challenging project in the past. This is the time when you use it as an example to prove your skills.\nRemember to not point fingers and explain the problem without making it sound like there was any negligence on your part. It also helps to mention what you learned from the experience.\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy\n\nUI UX Designer Interview Questions for Intermediate",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is your design inspiration?",
        "answer": "When an interviewer asks you this question, they want to know that there’s something that motivates you and that you are excited to keep learning.\nYou can talk about your favorite design blogs, magazines, etc. The following is a list of blogs you can follow:\nUX Booth\nBoxes and Arrows\nSmashing Magazine\n52 Weeks of UX\nGet our UI/UX design course in Bangalore and master UI/UX design from the basics!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. How do you decide which features to add to your design?",
        "answer": "This is a contextual question, so it is best to use real examples to explain why you would choose or reject it. Take them through the entire process. Tell them how you would address the business goals and user requirements:\nTarget market\nTarget market’s goals\nThe problem",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What research methods do you use?",
        "answer": "You can tell the interviewer about the type of research you use. If budget constraints limit your options, you can mention your utilization of online surveys. However, you can express your preference for conducting more in-person interviews if given the opportunity. By sharing this information, you convey your adaptability to resource limitations while expressing a desire for more immersive research approaches.\nThe key point is to let them know that you know about the research process. Tell them about the methods you use and the methods you wish to use.\nDo you want to know how much a UI/UX designer earns? Check out our blog on UI/UX designer salary!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are your biggest strengths?",
        "answer": "The best way to do this is to talk about your strengths keeping the company’s requirements in mind. You can prepare for your next interview by going through the job description carefully.\nLet’s look at this job description template for a UX designer on Glassdoor for example:\n\nAccording to this template, the company wants someone who can “assess user experience and ease of design”. They also want someone who will “build storyboards to conceptualize designs’, and someone who will “encourage cooperation and teamwork”. Keeping these in mind, you could say your biggest strengths are:\nEmpathy: You can understand the needs of the users to help make the easiest design for them possible.\nCreativity: You can conceptualize design ideas and put them together on storyboards for the entire team to understand.\nCollaboration: You work well in teams and you know different people can bring different perspectives to the table.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is your biggest weakness?",
        "answer": "Let’s work with another job description template for this question.\n\nAccording to the template, the company wants someone who will “ask smart questions”. They also want someone who can “identify design problems”. Keeping these in mind, you can sell your weaknesses as something that would still benefit the company.\nTell them you are a curious person who wants to know everything and how that could sometimes be nagging.\nYou can also tell them that you tend to be a little too critical of things at times and that helps identify problems that most others would miss.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. How do you handle negative feedback?",
        "answer": "Don’t give a one-word answer and say “well”. Explain how you’re open to all sorts of feedback and it helps you become a better person. You can talk about some feedback that you received and how you handled it.\nYou could mention how a previous boss was very quick with negative feedback but you took it as constructive criticism. Talk about how taking feedback from within the company is much better than waiting for it to come from actual customers. Talk about working together as a team and that you believe that if there’s something you could do better you’d like to discuss it.\nEnroll in the premier UI UX design course in Bangalore today! Take the first step towards a fulfilling career in the world of user experience.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Have you ever disagreed with your team’s recommendation? What did you do?",
        "answer": "The best answers are data-driven. You need to remember that. Tell the interviewer that you like using data and proven results to make any recommendations or business decisions.\nYou could talk about the time you disagreed with your team’s recommendation because of the user research you conducted. Your research had shown you that the customers weren’t responding positively to the team’s recommendation. Suggest conducting another round of usability testing so you can utilize A/B testing.\nRemember that disagreements should be solved with objective data rather than subjective opinions.\nWant to know about the UI/UX designer’s roles and responsibilities? Check out our blog on a UI/UX designer job description!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What excites you about this position?",
        "answer": "All employers want to know that you’re excited about the position you’ve applied for. You can be excited about the company and the position – but these are two different things.\nReference your career goals while answering the question. Tell them how this position will help you get better or teach you new skills. Also, tell them about the other skills and experience you have that make you an ideal candidate for this role.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Where do you see yourself in five years?",
        "answer": "We get that planning long-term could be difficult. You don’t need to have an exact five-year plan but you should at least have some idea of it.\nIf this is a career path that interests you, we’d hope you’d stay. You can tell them what this career path looks like for you. Is there a field of UX that you want to master? If that’s the case, you can explain how this position is going to help you get there. Or do you want to become a principal UX designer? That won’t really be achieved in five years but you can explain what you could do in the next five years to get closer to that goal.\nYou should also make it clear that you’d want to be in the company.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What are some of the biggest challenges you’ve faced as a UX designer?",
        "answer": "This is one of the common UX designer interview questions asked. While answering this question, always use examples. Use something from your portfolio to demonstrate the challenges you have faced as a UX designer. Talk about a project that made you work on something challenging and how it helped you develop a new skill.\nThey want to know how you solve problems. They also want to know how you handle pressure. Talk about how you handle the circumstances.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What design methods do you use?",
        "answer": "The interviewer is keen to assess your knowledge with multiple design methodologies and your proficiency in applying them. You have the opportunity to elaborate on the techniques you have utilized in previous experiences and articulate the reasons behind your comfort with each. The following list of design techniques is provided for your reference:\nValue proposition: This is the most important one as it tells you the important things about the product – what it is, who it is for and how it will be used.\nProduct strategy: The product strategy helps UX designers understand the particular target audience, and focus on the product, and the consumer attributes.\nUser interview: Conducting user interviews helps get important qualitative information from the users.\n\nUX Designer Interview Questions for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. How do you deal with research and usability testing?",
        "answer": "This presents another chance for you to share your past experiences. Discuss how the research you conducted, either individually or as part of a team, played a crucial role in achieving successful product outcomes. Additionally, you can elaborate on a specific instance where conducting usability testing provided invaluable insights.\nUse this opportunity to outline your approach to research and usability testing, and illustrate how you have effectively managed such processes in previous instances.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. Tell us about a design example that solved a business problem.",
        "answer": "You could answer this question by referencing your UI/UX design Portfolio and telling them about a design that you worked on that solved a big business problem. You could also talk about a real-life example of some brand that benefitted from improved design.\nMake sure to go into all aspects of the design and explain the problem well enough before you go into explaining how it helped. Statistics always help.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. Describe universal design.",
        "answer": "When considering this question, it is most effective to adopt an empathetic perspective. Universal design aims to create solutions that are accessible, usable, and comprehensible to individuals of all abilities, disabilities, ages, and sizes. A design that is truly universal should have the capacity to fulfill the requirements of anyone who wishes to utilize it.\nYou can go into detail and explain the two approaches to universal design:\nUser-Aware Design: includes as many people as possible by pushing mainstream product designs.\nCustomizable Design: makes sure the design can adapt to the needs of specific users.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. How would you make a product accessible to differently-abled users?",
        "answer": "You can start by talking about universal design and what it is. Explain why you like them – what features make them customer-friendly, and do they inspire you?\nAdapt to different platforms: It’s important to optimize the website or app so it can work well on various devices.\nPrioritize scalability: Your product needs to be durable. If it crashes during a high influx of activity, you will lose customers.\nTake user feedback: Your product will be universally accessible if it incorporates the needs of the users you are catering to.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. What are your favorite apps or websites and why?",
        "answer": "Mention your favorite apps and website. Explain why you like them – what feature makes them customer-friendly, and do they inspire you?\nYou can use the following for example:\nGoogle – Google is the perfect example of a good functional UX design. Just one search area is a great customer-friendly element.\nNetflix – Netflix is pretty easy to operate and it uses an algorithm to recommend stuff based on the user’s viewing history. This helps in delivering a personalized, easily understandable interface for the user.\nDuolingo – The app makes learning fun. The entire interface is gamified so users get the feel of playing a game instead of learning.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. Describe some design leaders that you follow?",
        "answer": "If you want to learn more about UX design, it’s a good idea to follow influential UX designers. Here are a few to get you started:\nLuke Wroblewski: Luke Wroblewski is a Product Director at Google. He’s known for his expertise in digital product design and has worked on designs and software used by billions of people.\nFarai Madzima: Farai Madzima is the UX Lead at Shopify and organizes the Pixel Up! Conference. He has created innovative banking products used in Africa.\nWhitney Hess: Whitney Hess is the CEO of Heart Work and hosts the podcast “Designing Yourself.” She’s a respected figure in the UX design industry.\nGraeme Fulton: Graeme Fulton manages the Tea Room at Prototypr.io, a website that provides the latest design tools. He’s a valuable resource for staying updated on cool design tools.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Who are your design heroes?",
        "answer": "You can mention names from the previous answer or talk about some personal design heroes that you’ve worked with earlier, or someone who inspired you.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. What are some UX-related publications that you read?",
        "answer": "UX Magazine\nUXer Talks\nSmashing Magazine\nAwwwards\nDesign Shack",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Do you have a product idea that you would want to build in the future?",
        "answer": "You can use this opportunity to describe your dream project. Talk about the product and make sure you go in-depth about its UX design. Tell them who the target audience will be and how you personalize the experience for them.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. How would you improve the UX of our product?",
        "answer": "It is important that you be thorough with their product before you go in for the interview. With this UX designer interview question, they are trying to figure out whether you’ve done your homework. Try to answer this with as much honesty as possible without sounding arrogant. Give them a humble review of their product and suggest changes that you could bring.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. How do you conduct the UX evaluation of a product?",
        "answer": "As a UX designer, you need to know how to conduct a UX evaluation for a product. You could have your favorite methods or techniques that you prefer. You can mention them here.\nSome UX evaluation methods are given below:\nAesthetics Scale – This method identifies the aesthetic quality of websites. It defines the two dimensions of user perception – classical aesthetics and expressive aesthetics.\nAudio Narrative – In this method, users narrate their experiences in the form of a story. This story is recorded.\nControlled Observation – People are called to a controlled environment where they test the colors or audio of the system. The data is collected in the form of facial expression videos, etc.\nEmotion Cards – Users are asked to test web or mobile applications where they are provided with cards. These cards would either have a preset emotion on them or it’s just a blank field. Users fill them in when they use the product.\nLiving Lab Method – In this method, research is conducted on the behavior of users in their natural living environments. This helps in understanding the process of making technologies that respect life’s complexities.\nProduct Personality Assignment – Users go through some product designs and answer a questionnaire assigning different personalities to each design. They also have to explain the reason behind their decision.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. What are the analytical tools and KPIs that you based your previous evaluations on?",
        "answer": "You can talk about various UI/UX design tools and KPIs you used when conducting a UX evaluation earlier.\nSome analytical tools you could talk about are given below:\nCrazy Egg – It’s one of the simplest heatmap tools.\nGood Data – It’s a BI solution that is cloud-based. It can combine multiple data sources to provide helpful reports.\nKissmetrics – It is useful in creating reports and funnels based on customer behavior.\nSome KPIs to consider are as follows:\nTask Success Rate – The task success rate helps you measure the number of correctly executed tasks.\nTime-on-Task – This describes the time that a user spends on completing a task.\nUser Error Rate – This is the number of times a user makes a wrong entry.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. What are the key differences between designing for desktop and mobile?",
        "answer": "The interviewer wants to make sure you’re aware of the design differences between desktop and mobile. You can discuss the following differences:\nScreen size – There is an obvious difference between the screen sizes for desktop and mobile. That affects the layout design. Desktop apps can support fixed navigation bars while mobile apps have to be limited to pull-out menus.\nInteraction – While desktops can take full advantage of the cursor’s interactivity, mobile apps don’t have that feature. Users have to use gestures like swiping, shaking, or poking in mobile apps.\nOrganizing content – In desktop apps, we can use the multi-column format offering way too many options in layouts and positioning. Mobile apps have to resort to scrolling.\nFunctionality – Desktops are preferred for longer, more involved tasks while mobiles are preferred for quicker tasks.\nAre you preparing for a job interview? Check out our blog on UI developer interview questions!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "ux-designer"
    }
]